<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Releases on Apache Ozone</title>
    <link>/ozone/release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Releases on Apache Ozone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Apache Software Foundation</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/ozone/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.4.1-alpha available</title>
      <link>/ozone/release/0.4.1-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ozone/release/0.4.1-alpha/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 0.4.1-alpha is released with following features:
 Ozone Native ACL support First class K8s support Stability improvements  This is an alpha release and not production ready.
 Image credit: Catholic 85, Biscayne, CC-BY-SA-4.0
The haiku is inspired work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.4.0-alpha available</title>
      <link>/ozone/release/0.4.0-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ozone/release/0.4.0-alpha/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 0.4.0-alpha is released with following features:
 Hadoop Delegation Tokens and Block Tokens supported for Ozone. Transparent Data Encryption (TDE) Support - Allows data blocks to be encrypted-at-rest. Kerberos support for Ozone. Certificate Infrastructure for Ozone - Tokens use PKI instead of shared secrets. Datanode to Datanode communication secured via mutual TLS. Ability secure ozone cluster that works with Yarn, Hive, and Spark. Helm/Skaffold support to deploy Ozone clusters on K8s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.3.0-alpha available</title>
      <link>/ozone/release/0.3.0-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ozone/release/0.3.0-alpha/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone 0.3.0-alpha is released.
 A new S3 compatible rest server is added. Ozone can be used from any S3 compatible tools (docs, HDDS-434) Ozone Hadoop file system URL prefix is renamed from o3:// to o3fs:// (HDDS-651) Extensive testing and stability improvements of OzoneFs. Spark, YARN and Hive support and stability improvements. Improved Pipeline handling and recovery. Separated/dedicated classpath definitions for all the Ozone components. (HDDS-447)  This is an alpha release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.2.1-alpha available</title>
      <link>/ozone/release/0.2.1-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ozone/release/0.2.1-alpha/</guid>
      <description>This is the first version of Apache Hadoop Ozone. Ozone is an Object store for Hadoop built using Hadoop Distributed Data Store.
This release is fully functional, but alpha quality.
 Image credit: Ken Lane, Acadia, CC-BY-NC-SA-2.0</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>