<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concepts on Ozone</title>
    <link>/concept.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Ozone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/concept/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/concept/overview.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/concept/overview.html</guid>
      <description>Ozone is a redundant, distributed object store optimized for Big data workloads. The primary design point of ozone is scalability, and it aims to scale to billions of objects.
Ozone separates namespace management and block space management; this helps ozone to scale much better. The namespace is managed by a daemon called Ozone Manager  (OM), and block space is managed by Storage Container Manager (SCM).
Ozone consists of volumes, buckets, and keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozone Manager</title>
      <link>/concept/ozonemanager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/concept/ozonemanager.html</guid>
      <description>Ozone Manager (OM) is the namespace manager for Ozone.
This means that when you want to write some data, you ask Ozone Manager for a block and Ozone Manager gives you a block and remembers that information. When you want to read that file back, you need to find the address of the block and Ozone Manager returns it you.
Ozone Manager also allows users to organize keys under a volume and bucket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Container Manager</title>
      <link>/concept/hdds.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/concept/hdds.html</guid>
      <description>Storage container manager provides multiple critical functions for the Ozone cluster. SCM acts as the cluster manager, Certificate authority, Block manager and the Replica manager.
 Cluster Management  SCM is in charge of creating an Ozone cluster. When an SCM is booted up via init command, SCM creates the cluster identity and root certificates needed for the SCM certificate authority. SCM manages the life cycle of a data node in the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datanodes</title>
      <link>/concept/datanodes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/concept/datanodes.html</guid>
      <description>Datanodes are the worker bees of Ozone. All data is stored on data nodes. Clients write data in terms of blocks. Datanode aggregates these blocks into a storage container. A storage container is the data streams and metadata about the blocks written by the clients.
Storage Containers A storage container is a self-contained super block. It has a list of Ozone blocks that reside inside it, as well as on-disk files which contain the actual data streams.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>