<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache Ozone</title>
    <link>/ozone/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Apache Ozone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Apache Software Foundation</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/ozone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.2.1-alpha available</title>
      <link>/ozone/release/0.2.1-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ozone/release/0.2.1-alpha/</guid>
      <description>This is the first version of Apache Hadoop Ozone. Ozone is an Object store for Hadoop built using Hadoop Distributed Data Store.
This release is fully functional, but alpha quality.
 Image credit: Ken Lane, Acadia, CC-BY-NC-SA-2.0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hadoop Ozone Releases</title>
      <link>/ozone/downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ozone/downloads/</guid>
      <description>To verify Hadoop Ozone releases using GPG:  Download the release hadoop-ozone-X.Y.Z-src.tar.gz from a mirror site. Download the signature file hadoop-ozone-X.Y.Z-src.tar.gz.asc from Apache. Download the Hadoop KEYS file. gpg &amp;ndash;import KEYS gpg &amp;ndash;verify hadoop-X.Y.Z-src.tar.gz.asc  To perform a quick check using SHA-256:  Download the release hadoop-ozone-X.Y.Z-src.tar.gz from a mirror site. Download the checksum hadoop-ozone-X.Y.Z-src.tar.gz.mds from Apache. shasum -a 256 hadoop-ozone-X.Y.Z-src.tar.gz  All previous releases of Hadoop Ozone are available from the Apache release archive site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>/ozone/docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ozone/docs/</guid>
      <description>Documentation is also part the binary release packages and available online from the running Storage Container Manager or Ozone Manager webui.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>/ozone/qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ozone/qa/</guid>
      <description>How can I contribute The contribution process is the same as for any other Hadoop subproject. The Ozone Contribution Guidelines is available from the wiki.
Does it mean a new Hadoop server component? Both Ozone and HDDS requires one additional master component - Ozone Manager and Storage Container Manger, respectively. The worker parts of Ozone/HDDS can be started as a HDFS Datanode plugin or standalone.
How can I try it out?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>