<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Ozone</title>
    <link>/tools.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Ozone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Configurations</title>
      <link>/tools/genconf.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/genconf.html</guid>
      <description>Genconf tool generates a template ozone-site.xml file at the specified path. This template file can be edited to replace with proper values.
ozone genconf &amp;lt;path&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audit Parser</title>
      <link>/tools/auditparser.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/auditparser.html</guid>
      <description>Audit Parser tool can be used for querying the ozone audit logs. This tool creates a sqllite database at the specified path. If the database already exists, it will avoid creating a database.
The database contains only one table called audit defined as:
CREATE TABLE IF NOT EXISTS audit ( datetime text, level varchar(7), logger varchar(7), user text, ip text, op text, params text, result varchar(7), exception text, UNIQUE(datetime,level,logger,user,ip,op,params,result))
Usage: ozone auditparser &amp;lt;path to db file&amp;gt; [COMMAND] [PARAM]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCMCLI</title>
      <link>/tools/scmcli.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/scmcli.html</guid>
      <description>SCM is the block service for Ozone. It is also the workhorse for ozone. But user process never talks to SCM. However, being able to read the state of SCM is useful.
SCMCLI allows the developer to access SCM directly. Please note: Improper usage of this tool can destroy your cluster. Unless you know exactly what you are doing, Please do not use this tool. In other words, this is a developer only tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing tools</title>
      <link>/tools/testtools.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/testtools.html</guid>
      <description>Testing is one of the most important part during the development of a distributed system. We have the following type of test.
This page includes our existing test tool which are part of the Ozone source base.
Note: we have more tests (like TCP-DS, TCP-H tests via Spark or Hive) which are not included here because they use external tools only.
Unit test As every almost every java project we have the good old unit tests inside each of our projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>